Here's my day, so far.
这就是我的一天
Went to jail, lost the girl of my dreams and got my butt kicked.
蹲过监狱 失去我爱的女孩 还被臭打了一顿
Pretty good.
很好
Still, things could be a lot worse.
情况可能会更糟糕
Oh, that's right, I'm falling to my death.
对了 我马上要摔死了
Guess they can't.
不是吧
How did it all come to this, you ask?
你会问 这是怎么回事?
My end starts at the beginning.
我的结局在开始就被注定
The very beginning.
从出生开始
Yes, that's me.
没错 那就是我
I had a fairly standard childhood.
我有过短暂但正常的"童"年
I came from what you might call, a broken home.
我出身在一个通常所说的 破碎的家庭
Literally, broken.
破碎是字面上的
I was eight days old and still living with my parents.
出生八天后就再也没见过父母
How sad is that?
有够悲催的吧?
Clearly it was time to move on.
命运齿轮开始转动
Here is your, Minion, he will take care of you.
这是Minion 它会照顾你
And here is your binkie.
拿好你的奶嘴
You are destined for ...
你命中注定会...
I didn't quite hear that last part.
我没听清最后半句
But it sounded important.
貌似很重要
Destined for, what?
命中注定 干什么?
I set out to find my destiny.
我出发去寻找命运
Turns out a kid from the Blaupunkt quadrant had the exact same idea.
看来另一个来自蓝宝象限的孩子也这么想
That was the day I met, Mr. Goody-two-shoes.
那天我遇见 "比别人都强" 先生
And our glorious rivalry, was born!
咱们的最佳对手竞争拉开了序幕
Could this be what I was destined for?
啊 这就是我的命运?
A dream life filled with luxury?
如梦如幻的奢华生活?
Apparently not.
显然不是
Even fate picks its favorites.
就连命运也挑喜欢的
No big deal.
没什么大不了
A much different fate awaited me.
一个截然不同的未来等着我
A baby.
是小宝宝哎
How thoughtful.
考虑太周到了
Oh yes, yes. I saw it and thought of you.
没错 我看见他就想起你
Luckily I found a lovely little place to call home.
总算有个小地方是我家了
Can we keep it?
我们可以养他吗?
A place that taught me the differences between right...
那里教我什么是对...
...and wrong.
...什么是错
Mr. Goody-Two-Shoes on the other hand,
而 "比别人都强" 先生
had life handed to him on a silver platter.
衣来伸手 饭来张口
Our baby can fly.
咱家的宝宝会飞哎
Yes, yes. Nothing but the best for you, Darling.
没错 你的都是最好的 亲爱的
The power of flight, invulnerability, and great hair.
他有飞行力 刀枪不入 发型也不错
But I had something far, far greater,
但有项我比他强的多
My amazing intellect.
那就是聪明才智
A knack for building objects of mayhem.
我能把犯罪工具造得出神入化
After a few years, and with some time off for good behavior.
几年后 因为表现良好
I was given an opportunity to better myself through learning.
我被允许上学来改造自己
At a strange place called shh-ool.
那个奇怪的地方叫学 "笑"
It was there that I once again ran into Mr. Goody-Two-Shoes.
在那里我又遇到了 "比别人都强" 先生
He had already amassed a gigantic army of soft-headed groupies.
显然他已经有N个没脑子的仰慕者了
He bought their affections with showmanship, and extravagant gifts of deliciousness.
他靠生动表演和香喷喷的米花 讨大家喜欢
So I too would make this 'popped-corn' and win over those mindless dregs.
哼 看我的 "爆玉米花" 让这群呆子大吃一惊
Lights out!
熄灯了!
That's when I learned a very hard lesson.
那次我学到了艰难的一课
Good receives all the praise and adulation.
英雄生来满载赞扬和奉承
While evil is sent to quiet time in the corner.
坏蛋就活该面壁思过
So a fitting end wasn't really an option.
于是我注定无法跟别人相处
While they were learning the itsy bitsy spider.
当他们在学可爱小蜘蛛时
I learned how to dehydrate animate objects.
我学会怎么给活物脱水
and rehydrate them at will.
和怎样任意再水化它们
Some day’s it felt like it was just me and Minion, against the world.
有时感觉只有Minion和我在一起 与全世界为敌
No matter how hard I tried.
不管怎么努力
I was always the odd man out.
我永远都不合群
The last one picked.
是剩下的那个
The screw-up, the black sheep.
永远一团糟 是害群之马
The bad boy.
是不良少年
Was this my destiny?
这就是我的命运?
Wait! Maybe it was.
等等! 也许没错
Being bad is the one thing I'm good at.
当坏蛋不就是我最擅长的吗
Then it hit me.
我恍然大悟
If I was the bad boy.
如果我是个坏孩子
Then I was going to be the baddest boy of them all.
我就要坏到彻底
I was destined to be a super villain.
我注定会成为超级大坏蛋
And we were destined to be rivals.
我们注定是对手
The die had been cast.
命运就这样决定了
And so began an enduring epic, life long career.
我的永恒史诗 毕生事业就此拉开序幕
And I loved it.
我爱这项事业
Our battles quickly got more elaborate.
我们的战斗很快变得越来越复杂
He would win some, I would almost win others.
他赢几次 我也不甘示弱
He took the name, Metro Man.
他有个大名 都市侠
Defender of Montrosity.
大都会守卫者
I decided to pick something a little more humble.
我的名字呢 就谦卑多了
Megamind.
超级大坏蛋
Incredibly handsome criminal genius, and master of all villainy.
史上最帅犯罪天才 精通各种恶行
Read on your own time. Open up.
下班了再看 开门
Oh, good morning, Warden.
早上好 典狱长
Great news, I'm a changed man.
好消息哦 我改过自新了
And I'm ready to re-enter society as a solid citizen.
作为可靠市民 我可以重返社会了
You're a villain, and you'll always be a villain.
你是个罪犯 而且永远是个罪犯
You'll never change.
你根本没有改过
And you'll never leave.
也就别想着离开
-You're fun. -You got a present in the mail.
- 你真搞笑 - 有人给你邮了份礼物
Is it a puppy?
是小狗吗?
From Metro Man. To count every second of your 85 life sentences.
都市侠给你的 "珍惜你85次无期徒刑的每分每秒吧"
That's funny, never thought Metro Man was the gloating type.
真搞笑 没想到都市侠也会落井下石
Oh but he does have nice taste.
但他品位确实不错
I think I'll keep it.
我帮你保管吧
Any chance you could give me the time?
能不能别再拖时间了?
I don't want to be late for the opening of the Metro Man museum.
今天都市侠博物馆开张 我可不想迟到
Oh no, looks like you're gonna miss it.
哦不 看来你要错过了
By several thousand years.
错过好几千年哪
Oh, am I?
噢 是吗?
Happy Metro Man day, Metro City.
大都会市民们 都市侠日快乐
It's a beautiful day in beautiful downtown where we're here to honor a beautiful man.
今日天朗气清 市中心整洁有序 我们即将迎来一位绅士的光临
Metro Man.
都市侠
His heart is an ocean that's inside a bigger ocean.
他的心胸似海洋 但更宽广
For years he's been watching us with his super-vision.
这些年 他的超级视力一直守卫着我们
Saving us with his super strength, and caring for us with his super heart.
超能力一直解救我们 博爱之心也关照我们
Now it's our turn to give something back.
现在是我们回报他的时候了
This is Roxanne Ritchi reporting live, from the dedication of the Metro Man Museum.
这里是Roxanne Ritchi为您 在都市侠博物馆落成典礼发回现场报道
Wow, okay, the stuff they make you read on the air.
刚才他们让你在广播里念的那一段
That's unfreaking believable, it's crazy.
真难以置信 都疯了吧
I wrote that piece myself, Hal.
那是我自己写的 Hal
What I was trying to say was,
其实我想说的是
I can't believe that in our modern society they let like actual art get onto the news.
在现代社会的新闻里还能出现艺术的闪光 真是难得啊
-Nice save, Hal. -What are we, like lets just get a coffee or something.
- 补得漂亮 Hal - 我们去喝杯咖啡什么的吧
Come on, it's time to get in the Metro Man day spirit.
今天可是都市侠的大日子
Well, if I were Metro Man Megamind wouldn't be kidnapping you all the time.
如果我是都市侠 决不会让大坏蛋绑架你那么多次
That's the first thing.
这是最重要的事
That's sweet of you.
你真贴心
And I'd be watching you, like a dingo watches a human baby.
我会像澳洲野狗看孩子一样看着你
-Mmm. -Okay, that sounded, Okay that sounded a little weird.
- 呃 - 听起来有点怪
A little bit, yeah.
确实有一点
And you're making a weird face, and that's making me feel weird.
你脸色怪怪的 我说什么好呢
Not love, we're not in love. I'm not saying I love you.
不是爱啦 我们又没谈恋爱 我不是说我爱你
Okay, I love you, whatever. I'm not saying like I'm in love with you.
好吧 我爱你 哎呀其实我也不是这个意思
I'm saying...Roxanne? Roxaroo?
我是说...Roxanne? Roxaroo?
Get back to work.
好好上班
The city doesn't pay you to loaf.
政府花钱不是让你游手好闲的
-Freeze! -Whoa, what are you doing, guys?
- 不许动! - 你们要干什么 伙计们?
It's ME! It's the Warden.
是我! 我是典狱长
Hey, open up.
喂 开门
Oh, you fools. He's tricked us.
你们个蠢蛋 都被他玩了
You were right.
你说得没错
I'll always be a villain.
我一直都会是个大坏蛋
Well hello good looking, need a lift?
哎呀帅锅 要搭车吗?
Certainly do, you fantastic fish you.
当然要啦 大美鱼
Get in the car, you.
快上车吧
Whoo, I'm free.
哟吼 我自由了
Thanks for sending me the watch, Minion.
你的手表棒极了 Minion
You got it, boss.
那还用说 老板
Punch it.
冲啊
All right, put your hands in the air.
来吧 把双手举高
Ladies and gentlemen, your Metro Man.
女士们绅士们 欢迎都市侠
-Who's your Man? -Metro man.
- 你们在等谁? - 都市侠
Yeah, Metro City!
你好 大都会!
Give me some, come on give it now. Give it to me. What?
来吧 把手都给我 怎么样?
Give it to me...all right!
来击掌吧...非常好!
Hey, Metro city.
你好 大都会
Hello, hey.
你好
You know, I just want you to bring it down a bit.
好了 大家都冷静一点吧
Boys, a little lower.
小伙子们 小点声
Thank you fellows.
谢谢
Let's get real for a moment.
我们现在说点实际的
That's right, that's right ha, ha, that's right.
没错 就是那样
Although getting a whole museum is super cool.
尽管有了自己的博物馆确实很酷
Super cool, you want to know what the greatest honor you've given me is?
很酷 但想知道我收过的最大荣誉吗?
Do you really want to know?
真的想知道?
Really?
真的?
I'll tell you.
我告诉你们
The greatest honor you've given me is...
你们给我的最大荣誉就是...
...letting me serve you.
...让我为你们服务
To help these people in Metro city.
帮助大都会里的市民
And at the end of every day.
每天临睡前
Well.
嗯
I often ask myself.
我常常问自己
Who would I be, without you?
如果没有你们 我会是谁?
Man screams: I love you Metro Man!
都市侠 我爱死你了!
And I love you, random citizen.
我也爱你 市民朋友
I tell you Minion, there's no place like evil lair.
我跟你说 Minion 没什么能比得上自己的邪恶巢穴了
I kept it cold and damp, just for you, sir.
我特意为您 让它保持潮湿阴冷
How do I look, Minion?
我看来怎么样 Minion?
-Do I look bad? -Disgustingly horrifying, sir.
- 看起来是个坏蛋吗? - 令人恐惧至极 先生
You always know what to say.
你拍马屁总能拍对地方
All the brain-bots certainly missed you, sir.
螺钉头们都想死你了 先生
Did you miss your daddy? Whose the menacing little brains?
想爸爸不? 最能逞能的是那个小不点?
You are, yes you are. Uh, uh! No biting, no, no, no.
是你啊 啊! 不许咬 不许咬哦
-No, no, no. You want the wrench? Go get the wrench. -Oh, look at that.
- 想要扳手吗? 快去抢咯 - 看它们高兴的
Now, back to work.
现在 开始工作
She's awake, Quick, to work.
她快醒了 快 准备好
-Miss Ritchi, we meet again. -Would it kill you to wash the bag?
- Ritchi小姐 我们又见面了 - 把袋子洗干净会死吗?
You can scream all you wish, Miss Ritchi. I'm afraid no one can hear you.
随心所欲地叫吧 Ritchi小姐 天皇老子也听不见哦
Wha..why isn't she screaming?
她...她为什么不叫?
Miss Ritchi, if you don't mind.
Ritchi小姐 如果你不介意的话
Like this...AHHHHH!
就像这样...啊啊啊!
That's, that's a poor ladies scream.
就是那样 可怜女士的叫法
-AHHHHH!!! -It's a little better.
- 啊啊啊!!! - 你比我擅长多了
Is there some kind of nerdy super villain website,
你们是在那个特傻的坏蛋网站上
where you get Tesla coils, and blinky dials?
买的这堆磁暴线圈和发光转盘吗?
Actually most of it comes from an outlet store in...
其实主要是在一家直销店...
Don't answer that.
闭嘴
Romania.
罗马尼亚那家
Don't! Stop! She's using her nosey reporter skills,
住口! 闭嘴! 别忘了她是个记者
on your weak willed mind to find out all our secrets.
她会利用你薄弱的毅力 获得我们全部机密
Such tricks...won't work... on me.
这点小把戏...哼 对我没用
-Please talk slower -Temptress.
- 能再说慢点吗 - 妖精
What secrets? You're so predictable.
你有什么秘密? 一眼就看到底了
Predictable, predictable?
一眼就 看到底了?
Oh, you call THIS predictable?
哈 那你来试试这个?
Your Alligators, yes.
鳄鱼而已嘛 没错吧
I was thinking about it on the way over.
来的路上我就想到了
What's this? BOOM!
那这个呢? 哇呜!
-In your face. -Clich?
- 小心你的脸 - 陈词滥调
No, look, watch.
不 等着看这个
Juvenile.
幼稚
-Shuck it all! -Tacky
- 启动! - 俗不俗啊你
-Oh, so sorry. -Seen it.
- 哎呀这个太可怕了 - 早看见了
-What's this one do? -Garish.
- 这个呢? - 真俗
Roxanne: Okay, the spiders new.
好吧 蜘蛛是个新点子
Spider?
蜘蛛?
Ee, Uh, yes!
啊 是的!
The "spee..ider". Even the smallest bite from arachnis deathicus
它叫 "织毒..蛛" 只要它轻轻咬你一口
Will instantly paralyze...OW!
你这辈子就瘫了...嗷!
Get it off!
把它扯掉!
Megamind: Ow! -Give it up, Megamind. Your plans never work.
放弃吧 大坏蛋 你的计划就没得逞过
Let's stop wasting time and call your boyfriend in tights, shall we?
别浪费时间了 赶紧给你男朋友打电话吧?
It is with great pleasure that I present to Metro Man, this new museum.
很荣幸由我把博物馆授予 都市侠
If you please.
请
Uh, hey, my kid can't see.
喂 我孩子看不见了
-Megamind. -Oh, bravo Metro Man.
- 超级大坏蛋 - 好极了 都市侠
Yes, I can play along too.
没错 我能和你们一起嘘哦
Should have known you'd try to crash the party.
早知道你会来砸场子的
Oh, I intend to do more than crash it.
恐怕没砸场子这么简单
This is the day you and Montrosity, shall not soon forget.
今天会让你和大都 "费" 永生难忘
It's pronounced Metro City!
是大都会!
Oh, potato, tomato, potato, tomato.
土了个豆 番了个茄 土豆 番茄
We all know how this ends.
我们都知道结局
With you behind bars.
就是你再入监狱
Oh, I'm shaking in my custom baby seal-leather boots.
哎呀 我穿着豹皮靴正发抖呢
You will leave, Montrosity.
准备永别大都 "费" 吧
Megamind: Or this will be the last you ever hear of,
否则这就是你最后一次听见她了
Roxanne Ritchi!
Roxanne Ritchi!
-Huh? -Roxanne!
Roxanne!
-Don't panic Roxie, I'm on my way. -I'm not panicking.
- 别慌 Roxie 我马上就到 - 一点都不慌
In order to stop me, You need to find me first, Metro Man.
想打败我 连我在哪都不知道 都市侠
We're at the abandoned observatory.
我们在废弃的天文台
-Ah ha. -NO! No we're not!
- 啊哈 - 不! 不是!
Megamind: Don't listen to her, she's crazy.
别听她瞎说 她疯了
Metro Man approaching, sir.
都市侠快到了 先生
Hold on a second.
等一下
Megamind: Oh, good heavens.
噢 天哪
You didn't think you were in the real observatory, did you?
没想到我们是在真的天文台吧 嗯?
Ready the death ray, Minion.
准备启动死亡射线 Minion
Death ray, readying.
死亡射线 准备待发
Megamind: Over here, old friend.
看这边 我的老朋友
Megamind: In case you haven't noticed,
友情提醒下
You've fallen right into my trap.
你中了我的计了
You can't trap justice. It's an idea, a belief.
正义永远不会被打败 这是理想 是信仰
Even the most heartfelt belief, can be corroded over time.
就算最虔诚的信仰 也被时间侵蚀
Justice is a noncorrosive metal.
正义是不锈钢
But metals can be melted by the heat of 're-vange'.
是金属就会被 "球" 恨这热融化的
It's 'revenge' and it's best served cold.
是仇恨 而且最好冷藏保存
But it can be easily reheated, in the microwave of evil.
有邪恶微波炉 想加热太容易了
Well I think your warranty is about to expire.
我猜它快到保修期了吧
Maybe I got an extended warranty?
我就不能延长保修吗?
Warranties are invalid if you don't use the product for its intended purpose.
如果你不正确使用产品 保修是无效的
Oh, girls, girls, you're both pretty. Can I go home now?
哎乖乖乖 你们漂亮极了 我可以回家了吧?
Of course, that is if Metro Man, can withstand the full concentrated power of the...SUN!
当然 不过前提是都市侠 可以承受无敌聚焦...太阳光!
FIRE!
开火!
Minion, fire...
Minion 开火...
Uh, it's still warming up, sir.
先生 还在预热
-Come again? -Warming up, sir.
- 你说什么? - 还是预热 先生
Warming up? The sun is warming up?
预热? 太阳也要预热?
One...sssecond...more.
就一小会
aaannnd....jussst.
马上...
Minion: Tippy, tappy tippy tap, tap, tip top more.
再来一点 上来了快了
-Honestly. -And we are ready, in just.
- 天啊 - 马上就好 再等
Oh! I told you to have things ready.
天! 跟你说过一切都准备好啊
I told you countless times.
跟你说过多少遍了
Why do you always blame me?
你干吗老是怨我?
My spider bite is acting.
我蜘蛛毒发了
Your plan is failing, just admit it.
承认吧 你又失败了
Yeah, good luck with that one.
是啊 希望下次成功
Whose side are you on?
你到底是哪一边的?
The losing side.
输的一边
-Thank you. -Uh, could someone stamp my frequent kidnapping card?
- 谢谢 - 能给我的被绑架常旅客卡盖章吗?
You of all people, know we discontinued that promotion.
你该清楚 那个促销早就不办了
-Chow, chow all. -Same time next week?
- 再见了 - 下周老时间?
What did he just say?
他刚才说什么?
Crab nuggets?
该死的金块?
Good lord, I'm trapped.
天啊 我飞不出去
What kind of trickery is this?
他又玩什么把戏?
You mad genius. Your dark gift has finally paid off.
你个狂人 你的诡计得逞了
It, it has?
成 成功了?
This dome is obviously lined with copper.
这个圆屋顶包着铜
-Yeah, so? -Minion: Sir!
- 没错 然后? - 先生!
Metro Man: Copper drains my powers.
铜耗尽了我的能量
Your weakness is copper?
你的弱点是铜?
You're kidding, right?
开玩笑呢吧你?
I don't think even he could survive that.
我觉得他这次死定了
Well, lets not get our hopes up just yet.
先别抱这么大的希望
-Look! -Metro Man.
- 看! - 都市侠
Metro Man...
都市侠...
Metro Man! AHHH!
都市侠! 啊~!
Oh god! Oh my god, oh!
哦 天哪! 哦 我的天哪 哦!
Megamind: Ewwww.
呃~~~
You did it, sir.
您成功了 主人
I did it?
我成功了?
He did it.
他成功了
Megamind: I did it.
我成功了
-You did it, sir. -I did it!
- 您成功了 主人 - 我成功了
-You did it.
- 您成功了 - 我成功了!
Montrocity is mine!
大都会是我的了!
Minion: You did it sir, you did it, sir. Yes you did.
您成功了 主人 您成功了 主人 是您成功了
Minion: All right people, hit it.
好了 唱吧
Hit it!
放音乐!
Drop 'em
放下枪
First off, what a turnout.
首先 真是意外啊
How wild is this, huh?
很疯狂 对吧?
All I did was eliminate the most powerful man in the universe.
我所做的只是消灭了全宇宙最强的人
Megamind: Are there any questions?
还有什么疑问吗?
Megamind: Come on..yes? You in the back.
问吧 后面那位
I'm sure we'd all like to know what you plan to do with us.
我肯定大家都想知道 你会怎么处置我们
And the city.
和这座城市
Good, I'm glad you asked that one.
很好 真高兴你能这么问
Imagine, the most horrible, terrifying evil thing you could possibly think of.
想想你们心中最恐怖邪恶的事情
And multiply it by...SIX!
然后再变本加厉个...六倍!
Megamind: In the mean time I want you to carry on, with the dreary normal things you,
但在这此间我希望 你们继续无聊乏味的
Normal people do.
日常生活
Let's just have fun with this, come on.
好好享受吧
And I will get back to you.
我会再回复你们的
Megamind: Now slam the door, really hard.
现在重重地摔门
They can...they can still see you.
他们...还是能看到你
- Now? - Yeah, you're still there.
- 现在呢? - 是的 你还在啊
Let's get going.
我们闪吧
Ahh, Minion.
啊 Minion
Did you think this day would ever come?
你有想过今天的到来吗?
No way, not at all, sir. Never, never in a million, I mean...
从没 一点都没想到 主人 从没 过个几万年也没可能...
Yes, I did.
我想过
Look at the intricate moon links.
看看这精美的吊顶
I'm looking, I'm looking.
我看着呢 看着呢
And what's this?
这是什么?
Looks like one of the giant monitors, in the lair.
看上去像基地里的大监视器
But it seems to only carry one station.
但好像只有一个画面
Oh, that sir is called a window.
哦 主人 那个叫窗户
-Window... -All the kids are looking through them.
- 窗户... - 所有孩子都通过它向外看
Oooo, I've never had a view before.
哦 我以前从没看到过
Montrosity Minion, it's all mine.
大都会 Minion 它是我的了
If my parents could see me now.
如果我的父母能看到我
Sir, I'm sure they're smiling down from evil heaven.
主人 我肯定他们会在恶棍天堂里微笑的
Well now that Mr. Goody-two-shoes is out of the way.
现在好好超人已经不能挡路了
I  can have, everything I want!
我可以拥有一切我想要的了!
And  there's no one to stop me.
而且没人能阻止我了
I know, I know. Always thirsty, never satisfied.
我知道 我知道 老是饥渴 都得不到满足
I understand you, little well dressed bird.
我能理解 小小漂亮鸟
Purposeless, emptiness, it's a vacuum isn't it. What's your vacuum like?
无目标 寂寞 真是空虚啊 你的空虚又是啥?
Hey, hey, hey! Not now, Minion.
嘿 嘿 嘿! 现在不行 Minion
I'm in a heated existential discussion with this dead-eyed plastic desk toy.
我和这死鱼眼的塑料玩具 正在进行关于自我存在的激辩
I...is something wrong, sir?
我...有什么不对吗 主人?
Just think about it.
仔细想想
We have it all.
我们拥有了一切
But we have nothing.
但又如此空虚
It's just to easy now.
现在得到太过于容易
I'm sorry, you've lost me, sir.
抱歉 我听蒙了 主人
-I mean, we did it, right? -Well, you did it, sir.
- 我们是成功了 对吗? - 是您成功了 主人
Yes you've made that perfectly clear.
是的 你说得很清楚了
-Then why do I feel so, Mel-on-cholly? -Huh?
- 那为什么我感觉这么 没气力? - 呃?
Unhappy.
不高兴
Oh, uh well, uh. What if tomorrow, we could go kidnap Roxanne Ritchi.
哦 那个 明儿我们去绑架Roxanne Ritchi如何?
That always seems to lift your spirits.
那一直对您都很给力
Good idea, Minion. But without him, what's the point?
好主意 Minion 但没有他 有啥意义呢?
-Minion: Him, sir? -Nothing.
- 什么他 主人? - 没什么
Okay, um, all right well just uh, that’s uh,
好吧 那么 那就...
something to consider and um,
当是备用选项吧
well, I think I'll just power down for a while then.
我想我还是休息一下吧
Roxanne: He was always there for us.
我们一直被他守护着
Roxanne: Dependable.
依靠他
Perhaps we took him for granted.
也许我们太习以为常了
Maybe we never really know how good we have it, until it's gone.
直到失去时才懂得去珍惜
We miss you, Metro Man.
我们想念你 都市侠
I, miss you.
我也想你了
Roxanne: And I have just one question for, Megamind.
我对超级大坏蛋只有一个问题
Are you happy now?
现在你高兴了?
This is Roxanne Ritchi reporting from a city without a hero.
这是Roxanne Ritchi 在这座无超人的城市为您报道
Roxanne: Coming up next. Are you ready to be a slave army? What you need to know.
接下来 你想当奴隶大军吗? 你们该知道的
Aaannd wrap that up and give it to a child on Christmas.
完美收尾 当是孩子的圣诞礼物
-'Cause we're done. -Okay, see you tomorrow, Hal.
- 因为我们完工了 - 好了 明天见 Hal
Wait, Roxie. I'm having a party at my house.
等等 Roxie 我家正要办个派对
Coming off the hook, or whatever. You should come over.
就算是放松一下什么的 你应该来玩
I got a DJ rented a bouncy house. Made a gallon of dip. It's gonna be sick.
我找了个DJ 租了个气垫屋 还有一堆酒 会很狂欢的
Oh, I don't know, Hal. I don't really fell like being around a bunch of people.
我不知道 Hal 我不太想去人多的地方
No, no, no. That's the best part, it'll  be like just you and me.
不 不 不 那更好 因为只有你和我
Wow, that uh, that's certainly very tempting.
哇哦 那很吸引人啊
-But, -I did hire a wedding photographer.
- 但是... - 我还请了个婚礼摄影师
That's just in case, we were like something crazy happened.
只是以防我们会做什么疯事
And you'd want a picture of it. Like maybe we should have this for like ever,
像是你想拍张照片 也许我们应该拍一张当是
like a memory, you know.
永久的纪念
Um, I'm gonna pass.
嗯 我还是不去了
I have some work here I need to do. Okay, bye.
还有事要做呢 好了 再见
So Thursday? Soft, Thursday?
周四如何? 周四可以考虑?
-Goodnight, Hal. -It's a soft yes, on Thursday.
- 晚安 Hal - 那就是有机会了 周四哦
What's, wrong with me?
我是怎么搞的?
Rented a bouncy house? Chick's don't like bouncy houses, they like clown's.
租了间气垫屋? 女孩又不喜欢那个 她们喜欢小丑嘛
Hal: Stupid van! Broke my finger!
该死的笨车! 弄断我的手指!
I've made a horrible mistake.
我犯了个大错误
I didn't mean to destroy you.
我不是有意要灭你的
I mean, I meant to destroy you.
我是说我有意要灭你
I didn't think it would really work.
但没想过会成功
What are we suppose to do? Without you, evil is running rampant through the streets.
我们接下来要怎么做? 没有你 恶人横行街头
I am so tired of running rampant through the streets.
我厌倦了横行街头
What's the point of being bad when there's no good to try and stop you?
没有英雄阻止 作恶又有何意思?
Someone has to stop, Megamind.
得有人来阻止超级大坏蛋
Bernard: Hey, we're closing soon.
嘿 我们要关门了
Oh, you scared me.
哦 你吓死我了
-Barry, right? -Bernard.
- Barry吧? - Bernard
Bernard, I was just well I was talking to myself.
Bernard 我只是...在自言自语
You may think I'm a little bit nuts.
你可能觉得我有点犯傻了
I'm not allowed to self guess directly.
我可没被允许乱猜测
Thank you, I just...
谢谢 我只是...
Bernard, I'll just be another minute.
Bernard 我过会就走
-Okay. -Thanks.
- 好的 - 谢谢
I had so many evil plans in the works.
我还是很多邪恶的计划没启用呢
The illiteracy beam.
文盲射线
Typhoon cheese.
台风奶酪
Robo sheep.
机器山羊
Battles we will now, never have.
那要是打起来一定空前绝后
You know we never had the chance to say goodbye.
我们都没机会好好道个别
So, it's good that we have this time now.
所以现在我们要好好叙叙
You know, before I destroy the place.
趁着我还没炸飞这里之前
Nothing personal, it just brings back to many painful memories.
不是针对你的 只是这里给了我很多悲惨的回忆
Hello, hello?
有人吗?
Roxanne!
Roxanne!
That's a pretty tasteless costume.
这装扮真没品
-Costume? -Megamind's head is not that grossly exaggerated.
- 装扮? - 超级大坏蛋的头没大得这么恶心
Oh you even made a cheap replica of his dehydration gun. How...
哦 你还做了把劣质的仿冒脱水枪 真是...
Hello, is someone there?
你好 有人在那吗?
Hello, who's there?
你好 谁在那?
Whoa! Hey, hey. Whew.
哇哦! 嘿嘿
It's just you, Bernard.
是你啊 Bernard
Oh, yes it's just me. Bernard.
是的 就是我 Bernard
Well thank you for letting me stay.
谢谢你能让我多呆会
Look I wouldn't stay for more than two minutes and thirty seven seconds if I were you.
要换是我 就不会多呆个2分30秒
We're having the walls and ceiling removed.
这里的墙和天花板都要换掉
Wow, that sounds like. Quite the renovation.
哇哦 听起来要大改造啊
I guess I'll. Guess I'll ride down with you then.
我跟你一起下去吧
I kept thinking he was going to do one of his last minute escapes.
我一直以为他能在最后一秒逃出生天
Yeah, he was really good at those.
是啊 他很在行的说
Oh, if only the world had a reset button.
哦 要是世界有重启按钮该有多好啊
I've looked into the reset button.
我也想要重启按钮啊
The size is impossible.
但做不到那尺寸啊
Oh, Bernard, I didn't know you had...feelings. Are you okay?
哦 Bernard 你也会...感慨啊 你还好吗?
Metro Man is gone. And now there's no one left to challenge Megamind.
都市侠已经去世了 现在没人能对抗超级大坏蛋了
Come on, Bernard.
拜托 Bernard
As long as there's evil good will rise up against it.
有邪恶的地方 就会诞生正义
Ohhh, I wish.
哦 我希望啊
I believe someone is going to stand up to Megamind.
我坚信一定有人会觉醒来对抗超级大坏蛋
-You really think so? -Yeah.
- 你真这么想? - 是的
I mean, it's like they say. Heroes aren't born, they're made.
就像老话说的 英雄不是天生的 而是被塑造的
Heroes can be made. That's it!
英雄是被塑造的 对了!
-All you need are the right ingredients. -Yeah.
- 我们要做的就是找到对的成分 - 是啊
-Bravery. -Yes.
- 勇敢 - 是的
-Strength. -Of course.
- 力量 - 当然
-Determination. -Imperative.
- 决心 - 必要
And a smidgen of DNA.
还有一点DNA
-With that, anyone can be a hero. -Yeah!
- 有了这些 任何人都能成英雄 - 对头
Oh, ho, ho, ho!
哦 哦 哦 哦!
I think we should run.
我想我们该跑了
Bye.
再见
Time to put the past behind us.
现在该忘记过去
Only the future...AHH!
展望未来了...哈!
Oh, I'm to close. I'm genuinely scared right now.
哦 我离得太近 真是吓到我了
Oh, I hope no ones seeing this.
哦 我可不希望有人看到
Create a hero? Wait, wait, what? Why would you do that?
造英雄? 等等 您为什么要这么做?
So I have someone to fight.
这样我才有对手啊
Minion, I'm a villain without a hero.
Minion 我是个没有对手的恶棍
A ying, with no yang.
缺少阳的阴
A bull fighter with no bull to fight.
没有牛斗的斗牛士
In other words, I have no purpose.
换句话说 我没了目标
Now, ask me how I'm going to do it.
现在问我如何造英雄
Go on, ask.
快问吧
How are you doing to do it?
您要如何造英雄?
I'm going to give someone, I don't know who yet.
我要找个人 现在还不知道是谁
Metro Man's powers. I'm going to train that someone to become Montrocity's new hero.
给他都市侠的超能力 还要把那人训练成大都市的新英雄
Over here, follow.
这里呢 跟着点
And then, finally I'm going to fight that hero. In an epic battle of good and evil.
最后我将和他对打 来一场正义与邪恶的大战
We could put everything back the way it was.
我们要将一切恢复正常
When the world was perfect.
到时世界就变得完美
And rosy. Behold, Minion.
和美好 听好了 Minion
Metro Man's cape.
都市侠的斗篷
Look closely.
仔细看清楚
Tell me what you see?
你看到了什么?
Dandruff?
头屑?
Yes, it's his DNA.
是的 是他的DNA
From this, we'll extract the source of Metro Man's awesome power.
有了这个 我们能提取都市侠的超能力
Minion: Sir, I think this is a bad idea.
主人 我觉得这是坏主意
Yes, It's a very wickedly bad idea. For the greater good of man.
是的 对一个好人来说 这是个非常坏的点子
But I'm saying this is a kind of bad, bad.
但我的意思那是个很糟糕的主意
Okay, you might think it's good in your bad perception.
好吧 因为您出发点是坏的 所以觉得是个好主意
But from a good perception, it is just plain bad.
但往好的方向想 这真的是个坏主意
Oh, you don't know what's good for bad.
哦 你又不知道 对坏蛋来说什么是好主意
Now we have just one shot at this.
现在我们只有一次机会
We must find a suitable subject.
得找到一个合适的人选
Someone who will do harm to mine. Who puts the welfare of others above their own.
那人会来对抗我 会舍己为人
What on earth is that?
这是啥声音?
Seems to be emanating from there, sir.
好像是从那里传出来的 主人
-O-llo, -Uh, it's hello.
- 哦好 - 呃 是你好
Hello, like that?
你好 这样吗?
-Bernard, it's Roxanne. -It's Roxanne.
- Bernard 是我Roxanne - 是Roxanne
Roxanne: I just want to thank you for inspiring me the other day.
我想谢谢你那天激发了我
-Oh, You've inspired me too. -Great!
- 哦 你也激发了我 - 很好!
Roxanne: It's time we stood up to Megamind and show him he can't push us around.
是时候翻身去对抗超级大坏蛋了 让他们见识下我们的厉害
Oh, oh really. She's so cute.
哦 哦 真的吗? 她真可爱
-I'm already hot on his trail. -Uh, huh.
- 我已经掌握他的行踪了 - 呃
And what gives you that idea?
你是怎么知道的?
-Uh, sir. -I just found his secret hideout.
- 呃 主人 - 我刚找到了他的秘密基地
How did she find my hideout?
她是怎么找到的?
Uh, how did you find his hideout?
呃 你是怎么找到的?
This is the only building in Metro City with a big observatory on the roof.
因为只有这座建筑有t望台
Okay, there's no way she'll find the secret entrance.
好吧 那她也找不到秘密入口
Oh! There's a doormat here that say's 'Secret Entrance'.
哦! 这里有个门垫 写着"秘密入口"
-Minion! -I kept forgetting where it was.
- Minion! - 人家老是忘记嘛
She'll discover all our secrets.
她会发现我们所有的秘密的
-Ohh, oh no! -You dim-witted creation of science.
- 哦 不好! - 你真是科学造出的白痴
- What? - Oh, not you Roxanne.
- 什么? - 哦 不是说你Roxanne
No, I was just yelling at my mothers, urn.
不是 我是在对我的妈妈们喊
Don't do anything, I'll be right there.
不要乱动 我这就来
Hal: Roxanne?
Roxanne?
Oh no, not again.
哦 不 又来了
Mega-Bernard: Roxanne.
Roxanne
Oh, I'm glad you're here.
哦 我真高兴你来了
Wait, how did you get here so fast?
等等 你怎么来得这么快?
Well, I uh. I happened to be speed walking nearby when you called.
那个 我 呃 你打给我时 我正在竞走
-In a suit? -Uh huh.
- 穿着西装? - 呃
It's called, 'Formal Speed walking'.
这是"竞走正式装"
But that's not important.
但这不重要啦
I better take the lead.
我还是来带路吧
This way looks exciting.
这里写着是出口
No, it says, exit.
不 那是出口
Uh, which is the abbreviation for 'Exciting', right?
呃 是"输出入口"的简称 对吧?
Roxanne: It's the mother load.
这里是主控室
-Ahh. -Wow.
- 啊 - 哇哦
-Just look at this thing.
- 看看这东西
You know, I really could use your help in deciphering all this.
我真的需要你来帮我解读一下
-Really? -You're an expert in all things Megamind, right?
- 真的吗? - 你对超级大坏蛋很有研究 对吧?
-Yes, right. -Together we could figure out his plan for the city and stop it.
- 是的 - 团结就能找到并阻止他的邪恶计划
Are you in?
你同意吗?
- Oh, what fun! - That's what I want to hear.
- 哦 乐意之至! - 这才对嘛
Minion, Code-Send in the brain bots.
Minion 接暗号 去把脑虫放出来
You know the whole point of a code is...
所谓的暗号是指...
Oh code-just do it, Minion.
哦 接暗号去做 Minion
Ahh, it's me you fools!
啊 是我啊 笨蛋!
Bernard!
Bernard!
It's daddy.
是爹地啦
Megamind!
超级大坏蛋!
What have you done with, Bernard?
你把Bernard怎么了?
Oh Bernard? Oh yes, I'm doing horrible things to that man.
哦 Bernard? 哦 是的 我要对那人施以酷刑
I don't want to get into it but, Lasers, spikes.
我不想细说 但有激光 长钉
Oh, please no, not the lasers and the spikes!
哦 不要 不要用激光和长钉!
You know the drill.
你还不清楚吗
Oh no, not the drill.
哦 不 不要用钻子
-Let him go. -Or what?
- 放他走 - 不然如何?
Or I'm going to find out what this weird looking gun does.
不然我就用你来试这怪枪
No don't! Don't shoot that gun.
不要! 别开枪
I'll just go get him.
我去带他出来
Unhand me you fiend!
放开我 恶魔!
It, its strength's to much.
太强大了
Oh, I work out.
哥可是练过的
Argh, it's really paying off. You're so fit, and strangely charismatic.
那你就要惨了 你这么苗条 而我是天生神力
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
I've did my best. But he's to fantastic.
我尽力了 但他太厉害了
Here, let me carry that heavy gun for you.
来 让我扛这大枪吧
I got this covered.
我能行
Let go, it's mine!
放手 那是我的!
Bernard, run!
Bernard 快跑!
Give it to me.
还给我
Oh no!
哦 不!
Roxanne.
Roxanne
Hal: Ow!
哦!
Who on earth is that?
那是啥东东啊?
Mega-Bernard: Roxanne!
Roxanne!
Bernard, you were right about that door being exciting.
Bernard 你猜对了 那门就是出口
This way.
这边走
What are you doing?
你干嘛?
This will stop them, here!
这能阻止它们 给!
Seems a bit extreme, doesn't it.
好像有点过火了吧
Just throw it.
快扔啊
Daddy's, sorry.
爹地很抱歉
-Wow, that was real exciting. -Yeah.
- 哇哦 真是太刺激了 - 是啊
-You were very strong in there. -I know.
- 你表现得很勇敢 - 我知道
I've never seen anyone but Metro Man stand up to him like that.
除了都市侠 我还没见谁能这样对抗他
What's going on?
出什么事了?
Hal, what happened?
Hal 怎么了?
I think a bee flew up my nose.
好像一只蜜蜂钻进我鼻子了
I was just about to make my frontal assault to rescue you,
我正想正面突击去救你
but like fifty ninjas started to attack me.
但好像有5个忍者挡住了我
So I had to beat them all up, and I did...
所以我得先制服他们 也成功了
-and they were all like crying, and stuff. -Wow.
- 他们被打得抱头痛哭 - 哇哦
Brave one, isn't he.
他很英勇 对吧
Who are you?
你是哪位?
Oh thi..., this is Bernard.
这是Bernard
-He's my partner. -Partner?
- 他是我的搭档 - 搭档?
Yes, yes partner.
是...是的 搭档
Well look partner, I'm her partner.
去你的搭档 我才是她的搭档
She doesn't know what she's saying. She's been through a traumatic experience.
她惊魂未定  胡说八道呢
I'd better take him home. Thanks again, Bernard.
我还是送他回家吧 谢谢了 Bernard
I'll call you tomorrow, partner.
明天打给你 搭档
Yeah, okay.
好的
I'd like that.
很荣幸
That was weird for everybody. 'Cause you accidentally, hugged him instead of me.
所有人都不正常 连你都抱他不抱我
Minion: Sir!
长官!
Minion whispers: Code-Did you find out who it was?
你找出它的身份了吗?
Huh? Oh, oh.
什么? 噢
Code-get the car.
车子呢
Code-right away, sir.
马上到 长官
-Bye. -See you tomorrow, Hal.
- 再见 - 明天见 Hal
I'll leave the door unlocked in case you want to check on me later.
我门不锁了 随时等你来检查
Megamind: Who is this man, we've infused with godlike power?
这人是谁? 他被灌入超人的力量
Ow, ow, whoa ho.
噢 哇
Well sir, his name's Hal Stewart. He's twenty eight years old.
报告长官 他叫Hal Stewart 28岁
No criminal record.
无犯罪记录
Actually, no records at all.
根本没任何记录
Apparently, this man hasn't accomplished anything.
看来这人一事无成
Not yet, Minion. Not...
别妄下定论 Minion
...Yet.
别
Could this day get anymore, funtastic?
还有更好的事发生吗?
So I will just go ahead and defuse him,
我马上消除他的力量
since this is clearly a mistake.
显然这是个错误
No, Minion. Something much more powerful at work.
不 Minion 更强大的力量就要出现了
This is no mistake.
这不是错误
It's destiny.
这是命运
Hal Stewart, prepare for your destiny.
Hal Stewart 迎接你的命运吧
Hal? Hal Stewart?
Hal? Hal Stewart?
Am I saying it right?
我说得对吗?
-Stewart. -Aaah.
- Stewart - 啊
Is this a robbery? 'Cause the lady across the hall has way better stuff than me.
打劫吗?大堂对面的女人比我有钱
Oh, look. It's Hal Stewart.
看 这是Hal Stewart
Quick, the spray.
快 喷雾
-Oops, all out. -Well use the forget-me-stick.
- 用完了 - 那就用失忆棒
Oh, right!
对!
Just look at him.
看看他吧
Minion: Well, he doesn't look quite the hero type to me.
他看上去不像个英雄
Oh, you're such a pill, Minion.
你个讨厌鬼 Minion
The power couldn't ask for a finer claim.
力量不能对外表要求太高
I smell hero.
我闻到英雄的味道
I smell something burning.
有东西烧起来的味道
I think it's working!
一定是起反应了!
Places, places, places, places...
就位 就位...
You have your disguise?
你可以易容吗?
What?
什么?
Ah, you look fantastic.
你看上去酷毙了
Rise, my glorious creation.
起来吧 我神圣的作品
Rise, and come to Papa.
起来 到爸爸这儿来
What's going on?
发生什么事?
-Easy my child. -Who are you?
- 放轻松 我的孩子 - 你是谁?
I sent  you to this planet to teach  you about justice.
我把你送到这个世界 为了教导你正义
Megamind: Honor, and nobility.
荣誉 和高尚
I am your father.
我是你的老爸
So you're like, my space Dad?
你就像 我的太空老爸?
Yeah, I'm like your space Dad.
是 我就像你的太空老爸
And you are, what?
你又是什么?
I'm your space, Step-Mom.
我是你的太空 后妈
I, I had some work done recently.
最近好好修饰过了
Is this some kind of dream?
这是在做梦吗?
This is a dream come true.
梦已经实现了
You've been blethed with unfathomamble power.
你被赐予不可估量的强大力量
What kind of power?
什么样的力量?
Unfathamomble.
深不可测的
It's un, without Fathom.
就是没法找到的
-Whoa -Yeah, we've come to guide you.
- 哇 - 我们来指引你
On your path to be Montrosity's new hero.
成为大都费的新英雄
And battle the super genius, of Megamind.
打败超级大坏蛋
I know this is a lot to take in.
我知道这很难理解
It may take months for you to come to grips..
你可能要花几个月练习控制力...
No frickin' way.
没门儿
I wasn't finished.
我还没说完呢
Wahoo! I'm going to be a hero.
哇! 我要变成英雄了
I'm going to be a hero.
我要变成英雄了
Thee Minion, he's perfect.
Minion 他太完美了
Aaannd, action!
开始!
- Someone help me. - I'm okay.
- 帮我一把 - 我没事
Zap, zap, zap.
杀 杀 杀
The flames of my evil burn bright. Now you thay thomething cool back at me.
我的恶魔之火已经点燃 现在你对我说些好听的
Look, it doesn't even hurt. Don't even feel it.
根本就不痛 感觉不到
No, no, no. Slow it down, and stop.
不 不 慢点 然后停下
I said slow down.
我说了慢点
Watch out.
当心
He's hopeless. HOPELESS!
他没救了 彻底没救了!
-Maybe we should change tactics? -You think so?
- 可能要改变方法? - 你这么想?
Oh, you know how boys are. They love video games.
男生嘛 都喜欢打游戏
I can throw a few parts together.
我能同时扔起很多部分
Can't...wait. LoL,  smiley face.
等不及了 LoL 笑脸
Can't wait for what, sir?
长官 等不急干吗?
Oh, that was such a funny story.
那件事太搞笑了
And brilliantly told, by the way.
当然 描述得也很棒
Okay, now you tell one.
好吧 轮到你讲了
Bernard, I never knew you were so funny.
Bernard 我以前从没发现你这么有趣
And, I never heard you laugh before.
而且也没听你大笑过
Yeah, it's been a while.
是呀 有阵子没笑了
Feels pretty good.
感觉很好
And, exit.
接下来 出口
You  don't get out much, do you?
你不经常出来吧?
Fun!
好玩!
I used to come here with my mother when I was a kid.
小时候经常和我妈来这儿
It was one of my favorite things to do.
那是我最喜欢的事之一
Now look at it.
现在呢
It's a dump.
变垃圾场了
Why are we cleaning up the City, sir?
长官 我们为什么要打扫城市?
Um, well we don't want to battle our new hero in a dump, now...do we?
总不想在垃圾堆里战斗吧?
They're all back.
一切都回来了
But how, why?
怎么会的?
Maybe Megamind isn't so bad after all.
可能超级大坏蛋不是想象中那么坏
That's it. Be free, my beautiful dove.
就是这样 放松点 我的小肥鸽
Wa haoooo
哇
Okay, okay, Metro Man and I, were never a couple.
都市侠和我从没在一起过
But I thought you two were...
但我觉得你们俩是...
I know, everybody did. It's just, well he was never really my type.
大家都这么想 只是 他不是我喜欢的类型
Really?
真的?
Okay, now you tell me something.
现在说说你吧
Something you've never told anyone.
没跟别人说过的秘密
Well, in shh-school.
在鞋..学校
None of the other kids really liked me.
同学都不喜欢我
I was always last one picked for everything.
所有事都是最后一个轮到我
Hmm, it's to bad that we didn't go to the same school.
真可惜我们不是一个学校
Hal, I think  you're ready for this.
Hal 你该试试这个了
Do I have a son?
给我儿子吗?
No, Hal, you make me laugh.
不 Hal 你真幽默
It stretches, it's for you.
有弹性的 这是给你的
Hey, what's the 'T' stand for?
"T"是什么意思?
Titan.
Titan (巨人)
Tighten? What's that suppose to mean?
紧身? 什么意思?
It was the only name I could trademark.
这是我唯一注册过的商标
Oh.
噢
Do you have someone special in your life, Hal?
有对你来说非常特殊的人吗 Hal?
No not yet, but.
不 还没有 但是
There's this really, really good looking one I've got my eye on, currently.
我正对一个漂亮女人目不转睛
That's very good. Romance is very inspiring.
那很好 爱情能带来灵感
-That's what I hear. -All you have to do, is save her.
- 我懂了 - 你要做的就是 留住她
Mega-space dad: And she'll be yours.
她就会属于你
-Who want's Churro's? -I do!
- 谁要吃油条? - 我要!
Hal: Thanks spaced out, momma.
谢谢你去太空买 妈妈
Mega-Space dad: On the count of three, unsheathe your Churro.
数到三 拔出油条
All together: One, two, three! To Titan.
1 2 3 为了Titan!
Mega-space dad: Tomorrow, you will fight Megamind.
明天你就要和超级大坏蛋一决高下
Mega-space dad: And the city will know your name.
整个城市会记住你的名字
The City's parks' restored to their original glory.
城市公园恢复原有风貌
The street's, the safest they've been.
街道变得很安全
The banks reopened.
银行重新开业
Has something happened to Megamind?
超级大坏蛋怎么了?
Has someone tamed this monster?
是否有人驯服了这只野兽?
This is Roxanne Ritchi cautiously optimistic, and pleasantly confused.
我是Roxanne Ritchi 带着谨慎的乐观和欣慰的疑惑报道
Well you seem in a very good mood tonight, sir.
看来今晚你心情不错 长官
Huh? Oh yes, how long is this going to take?
啊? 噢 是的 这要花多久?
Just a few alterations, sir. And I will be done with your most terrifying cape yet.
就一点小改动 我会做适合你的最恐怖的斗篷
I'm calling it, The Black Mambaaaaaaa...aaaa...aaa.
我称它为 黑蟒...蛇
Black Mamba, perfect. Ooo, gosh I am running late. I have to go.
黑蛇 太好了 天呢 我要走了 快迟到了
What, where, where are  you going, sir?
什么 你要去哪里 长官?
We have our debut battle with Titan tomorrow morning.
明早就要和Titan开战了
We haven't even tested your big battle suit yet.
还没测试你的战袍呢
You attend to the details, Minion.
具体细节交给你了 Minion
I have to, run a quick errand.
我有急事
You don't run errands.
你没什么好忙的
What's going on here?
发生什么了?
-What? -Oh, wait a minute.
- 什么? - 慢着
Are you wearing Jean-Paul Gaultier's, For Him?
你是不是为了他喷了 Jean-Paul Gaultier香水 ?
It's just my natural musk.
这只是平时的装扮
Now, where are the car keys?
车钥匙在哪儿?
Ahhh.
啊
Uh, uh, uh, uh. This is about Ms. Ritchi, isn't it.
啊 啊 是Ritchi小姐 不是吗?
Your going on a date with her.
你和她在约会
No my main man, get out of town.
少来了 我的朋友
Oh this is bad, this is bad. You've fallen in love with her.
你爱上她就糟糕了
You are forgetting your place, Minion.
别忘了你的身份 Minion
Now give me the keys.
给我钥匙
What happens when Roxanne finds out who you really are?
万一Roxanne发现你的真面目呢?
She will never find out.
她不会知道的
That's the point of lying.
这就是该撒谎的时候
Ahhh!
啊!
Honestly, If I didn't know any better I'd think this was your first day of being evil.
老实说 如果我没猜错 今天是你变坏的第一天
NO!
不!
This has gone far enough.
太过分了
Oh, that was really grown up.
还真成熟啊
Sir please, it's for your own good.
长官 听我说 这是为你好
Well what do you know.
你知道什么
I may not know much, but I do know this.
虽然我知道的不多 但我知道
The bad guy doesn't get the girl.
坏人得不到女孩的心
Maybe I don't want to be the bad guy anymore.
也许我不想再做坏人了
You heard me.
听见了没
Who are you?
你是谁?
-Now give me the keys. -NO!
- 给我钥匙 - 不!
My soul purpose in life is to look after you.
我的使命是照顾你
Well I don't need you to look after me.
我不需要你来照顾
What are you...what are you saying?
你...你说什么?
-You don't need me? -Let me make it clear.
- 你不需要我? - 跟你说白了
Code-I don't need you.
我不需要你
You know what, you know what.
你知道吗 你知道吗
Code-I'll just pack my thing and go.
我打包走人了
Code-Fine!
好的!
Code-Fine back.
好就好
Well good luck on your date.
祝你约会成功
-I will. -That doesn't even make any sense.
- 一定会的 - 这毫无意义
I know.
我懂
I know I am so close, I can feel it.
已经很接近了 我能感觉到
Okay, okay I just have to take a step back.
好吧 我该退一步想想
Wait a minute.
等等
Roxanne: Titan.
Titan
What's a Titan?
Titan是什么?
My super ears are burning.
我的顺风耳在燃烧
I usually just hear criminals. You haven't been naughty, have you?
我只听得见罪犯的声音 你不会这么调皮吧?
I'm totally messing with you. I'm totally messing with you.
开玩笑 开玩笑
The names Titan.
我叫Titan
-Titan? -Your very own heroic  guardian of pure awesome.
- Titan? - 你的专用英雄守护神
What's your name? Just kidding, I know everything about you.
你叫什么? 开玩笑的 我知道你的一切
Oh, oh! And I brought some flowers,
噢!我带来了一些花
Didn't know what you liked, so I just grabbed  you know, all of them.
不知道你喜欢哪一种 所以我全摘来了
Okay, you don't like flowers. Okay, uh, uh, forget the flowers.
好吧 你不喜欢花 那就忘了吧
-What do you want? -Thought maybe we could go for a little flight around town.
- 你想干吗? - 也许我们能去兜兜风
-Get to know each other first. -WHOA!
- 先了解对方 - 哇!
It's suppose to be very thrilling for you.
这对你来说有点刺激
Just what do you think you're doing?
你知道自己在干吗吗?
Oh are I moving to fast?
我飞得太快了?
You're probably right. I should just rescue you a few times before we get all romantic.
你说得对 在我们相爱之前 应该先救你几次
Whoops!
啊呀!
Saved you. You are lucky to have such a great hero here.
接住你 有大英雄守护你真幸运
Oh no. Somebody do something?
不 谁来帮帮忙?
Oh, right, right. Duh! I gotcha.
对 对 我来救你了
That was fun, you almost died. But I saved you.
真好玩 你差点死了 但我救了你
-Aaaah, building! -AH!
- 啊 大楼! - 啊!
Gotcha!
接住了!
Whoo, I'm sorry. What were you saying?
不好意思 你刚说什么?
I couldn't hear you over the sound of me saving your life.
我听不见 被我救你的声音覆盖了
Put me down, right now!
放下我 马上!
Okay, all right, all right, hold on.
好吧 好吧 抓紧了
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗?
I suppose I'm, a little crazy... about you.
我想我是有点疯狂...为了你
Who are you? Really.
你是谁? 说真的
Oooh, oooh, right. Well prepare to have your mind blown, little lady.
好吧 准备大吃一惊吧 小姐
-Tada! -Hal?
- 看! - Hal?
Yeah, isn't this great?
是啊 这不是很好吗?
Now there's nothing keeping us apart.
没有什么能把我们分开了
No, it's not great.
不 一点也不好
Wow, our first fight. This is so us, we're like an old married couple.
我们的第一次飞行 太浪漫了 就像一对老夫老妻
There is no us, okay. There will never be an us.
没有我们 我们永远不可能
But, I have powers.
但是我有力量
I have a cape, I'm the good guy.
我有斗篷 我是好人
You are a good guy, Hal.
你是好人 Hal
But you don't understand we need to find out why...
但你不明白为什么...
-Right now, -This isn't right.
- 现在 - 这样不对
-Listen to me, Hal. -You're suppose to be with me.
- 听着 Hal - 你应该和我在一起
I'm trying to warn you, Hal.
我在警告你 Hal
It's Tighten. It's TIGHTEN, not Hal.
是Titan 不是Hal
-Bernard. -Roxanne.
- Bernard - Roxanne
-Sorry I'm late. -Wow, your hair looks exciting.
- 对不起我迟到了 - 你的头发很刺激
Hmm, not the only exciting development of the night.
今晚不止是头发很刺激
Megamind's created a new hero.
超级大坏蛋创造了一个新英雄
And I know why.
我知道原因
It all makes sense now.
一切都说得通了
He missed getting his butt kicked, so he created a new hero to kick it for him.
他怀念被人踢屁股的感觉 所以创造英雄来对付他
But why did he pick, Hal?
但他为什么会选Hal?
Hal is the worst possible person you could pick.
Hal是最不可能被选的人
Wow, that's a lot to take in.
这很难理解
It, it boggles my mind.
让我大吃一惊
I am extremely boggled.
我也很惊讶
You know, I'm sure we'll get to the bottom of who's kicking who's butt.
谁踢谁的屁股一定会见分晓
But in the mean time.
但与此同时
Let's enjoy each other's company.
让我们先享受在一起的时光吧
I'm sorry, Bernard. Of course, your right,
抱歉 Bernard 你说得对
you know, I could use a breather.
我应该先喘口气
To, Bernard. For being the only normal thing in my crazy upside down world.
为了Bernard 为你是我疯狂世界中 唯一正常的人
To...being normal.
为了...正常
-Roxanne. -Yes?
- Roxanne - 怎么了?
Say I wasn't so normal.
如果我不是正常人
Say I was bald and had the complexion of a popular primary color.
如果我秃了 而且是有色人种
As a random, non specific example.
只是打个比方
Would you still enjoy my company?
你还会对我有兴趣吗?
Of course, you don't judge a book by its cover.
当然 不能以貌取人
Or a person from the outside.
或以外表看人
Oh, that's a relief to hear.
太让人欣慰了
You judge them based on their actions.
根据人的行为来评判
Well that seems kinda petty, don't you think.
我看起来有点小心眼 不觉得吗?
-You. -What, what?
- 你 - 怎么了?
Oh, don't look at me!
别看着我!
Just, just a technical glitch.
只是个技术错误
Don't look yet.
别看
My bad.
我错了
Where were we?
刚说到哪了?
Now, now, hold on.
别动
YOU!
你!
I can explain.
听我解释
What about everything you just said?
你刚才说的那些话呢?
About judging a book by it's cover.
关于以貌取人
Well let's take a look at the contents then, shall we?
先得看看目录好吗?
You destroyed Metro Man.
你毁了都市侠
You took over the city and then you actually got me to care about you.
你占据了城市并让我爱上你
Why are you so evil?
你怎么这么坏?
Tricking me?
耍我?
What could you possibly hope to gain?
你想得到什么?
Wait a minute.
慢着
Oh, I don't believe this.
我不相信
Do you really think that I would ever be with you?
你难道以为我会跟你在一起吗?
no...
没有...
Okay Minion, you were right.
好吧 Minion 你是对的
I was....less right.
我... 我也没错啦
We should stick to what we're good at.
我们还是重操旧业吧
Being bad.
做坏人
Minion...
Minion...
You there.
你
Yeah, you.
就你
Bring out, the 'Black Mamba'!
把黑蟒战袍拿来!
Okay, Titan it's time to go down, in style.
好了 Titan 是时候出来耍耍了
I hear there's a new hero.
我听说又冒出来个英雄
who dares to challenge my evil.
敢跟我过招
Where is the one they call, Titan?
叫什么来着 Titan?
Challenge me, if you dare.
有种你就来啊
Megamind playfully cries: Oh no, we're gonna crash.
噢 不 我们要掉下去了
This is embarrassing.
太丢人了
Ballsy and incipient.
莽夫 幼齿
Boneheaded, irresponsible.
愚蠢 没责任心
RUDE!
粗鲁!
Unprofessional, that's what this is.
不专业 说的就是你
Would Metro Man have kept me waiting?
都市侠会让我干等吗?
Of course not, he was a pro.
当然不会 人家很专业的
Hey, Megamind. You're actually the guy I want to see.
嘿 超级大坏蛋 我正想见你呢
Also, there's a door here.
而且 这儿又不是没门
Do you have any idea how long I waited for you?
你知道我等了你多久吗?
No, no, no, I totally understand what you're saying.
不 不 不 我完全能理解你
Could you just shut up for one second, I'm trying to beat this level.
你等会儿行不 我正打算通关呢
Were you even planning on showing up?
你有想过要来吗?
What's this?
这是什么?
Where did you get all this stuff?
这是哪儿来的?
It doesn't belong to me.
都不是我的
You stole it!
你偷的!
-Pretty cool, right. -Oh no, no, no. You're a hero.
- 很帅吧 - 不对 不对 你是英雄
Being a hero is for losers.
衰人才当英雄
It's work, work, work twenty four seven, and for what?
没日没夜地战斗 战斗 图什么呀?
I only took the gig to get the girl. And it turns out Roxanne doesn't want anything to do with me.
我作秀是为了把妹 结果发现 Roxanne根本不想跟我在一起
Roxanne Ritchi?
Roxanne Ritchi?
Yeah, Roxanne Ritchi.
是啊 Roxanne Ritchi
I saw her having dinner, and making googly eyes at some intellectual dweeb.
我看到她跟书呆子共进晚餐 眉来眼去的
Who needs all that noise.
谁喜欢这种破事
That's why I think, WE should team up.
所以我觉得我们应该联手
You? Wait! What?
你? 等等! 什么?
With my power, and your big headedness,
我的力量加上你的智慧
we could rule the city.
这城市就是我们的了
-You want to team up? -I even drew up some new costume designs.
- 你要联手? - 我还设计了我们的新造型
-See -Costume design?
- 看 - 造型?
You be the brain so you get a little brain wearing glasses on your costume, or something.
你负责出主意 所以衣服上有个脑子 戴副眼镜什么的
And since I'm the cool one, I'll have like two tanks sword fighting.
因为我是老大 应该揣上两把坦克剑
I can't believe you.
真不敢相信
All your gifts all your powers, and you squander them for your own personal gain.
你滥用这些才能和力量 满足一己之欲
-Yes! -NO!
- 是啊! - 不对!
I 'm the villain, you're the good guy. I do something bad, and you come and get me.
我才是坏人 你是好人 我干坏事 你来阻止我
That's why I created you.
所以我才创造了你
Yeah, right. You're nuts.
是的 没错 你是白痴
-Space Dad told me. -Look, I'm your Space Dad.
- 太空老爸告诉我 - 太空老爸就是我
You should be more like Metro Man.
你应该多跟都市侠学学
You tricked me?
你耍我?
Oh, don't like that, huh?
不乐意了?
Well there's more.
还有呢
I'm also the intellectual dweeb dating Roxanne.
那个和Roxanne约会的书呆子也是我
-No. -And we were smooching up a storm.
- 不 - 我们还法式热吻呢
Mmmore...Mmmore...Mmmore.
么么...么么...么么
When I get my hands on you I'm gonna,...
等我逮到你 我...
YES! Yes I know.
来了! 我知道
Bring me to justice. Oh god, how I missed this.
将我绳之以法 天哪 太怀念了
And the hero strikes the first blow.
英雄先下手了
But evil returns with a backhand.
不过恶魔也会有反击
YES!
太棒了!
Ahh...shhhh.
嘘
Come out you little freak!
滚出来 变态!
I want to see what that big brain looks like on the pavement.
看我把你打得屁滚尿流
You fell for the oldest evil trick in the book.
你入了本大爷的套啦
You little blue, twerp.
你这个蓝皮蠢货
En Garde!
来喽!
Oh, now that's the spirit.
就是这种感觉
Take, that, parry again!
吃我一招 再来!
Now it's time for some witty back and forth banter.
该来点有技术含量的了
You go first.
你先来
Look, I'm not sure where to go with that.
哟 我不知道这算什么招式啊
This one's for stealing my girlfriend.
这下是为了你抢走我女朋友
This one's for space Dad making a fool out of me.
这下是为了太空老爸耍我
And Megamind! This one's for Space, Step-Mom.
超级大坏蛋! 这下是为了太空老妈
You lied to her!
你辜负了她!
Oh, well done, I thought that pummeling went really, really well.
干得好 你打得好 太好了
I mean, I have a few notes.
我 我有点小建议
-Notes? -But they can wait.
- 建议? - 不过不着急
You can take me to jail now.
你可以送我去监狱了
Oh, no, no, no. I was thinking more like the morgue.
不 不 不 我觉得停尸房更好
-You're dead! -Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- 你死定了! - 哇 哇 哇
This isn't how you play the game.
不是这么玩儿的
Game over.
游戏结束了
Brain Bots.
小飞虫
I'm calling time out.
我要休战
Time out, time out!
休战 休战!
Brain bots. Initiate the fail safe.
小飞虫 启动保险系统
Guess what, Buster Brown?
没想到吧 大块头?
It's made from Copper. You're powerless against it.
这是铜做的 这下你不行了吧
It's a very safe metal used to defeat...
可保险了 用来对付...
Metro Man?
都市侠?
You, should stop comparing me to Metro Man.
你别再拿我和都市侠比了
Tighten: You can run Megamind, but you can't hide.
你跑得了一时 超级大坏蛋 可跑不了一世
Mayor: We're saved, we're saved!
我们得救啦 我们得救啦
What's your name, new hero?
您叫什么名字 新的英雄
-It's Tighten. -Thank you, thank you.
- Tighten - 谢谢您 谢谢
Tighten has freed us.
Tighten解放了我们
Oh I wouldn't say free.
我可没说解放
Tighten: More like, under new management.
应该说 我将带来新的秩序
What do you want?
你想干什么
-Titan's turned evil. -Congratulations, another one of your genius plans has backfired on you.
- Titan走上邪路啦 - 恭喜 你又一个天才计划弄巧成拙
And why did my doorman let you up?
门卫怎么会让你上来的
-Carlos? -What are you, no, no!
- Carlos - 你想干嘛 别关 别关
I need your help.
我需要你的帮助
Why do you need MY help?
你怎么会需要我的帮助
Because you're the smartest person I know.
你是我认识的最有智慧的人
Well you can't hide here.
你不能躲在这儿
Copper should  have worked, why didn't the copper work?
铜应该有用啊 怎么就失效了呢
The copper worked perfectly well the last time.
上一次明明效果超赞的
Copper? You're not making any sense.
铜? 你在胡说神马
Look, if we don't find Titan's weakness. He'll destroy the whole city.
听着 如果找不到Titan的弱点 他会把整座城市摧毁的
Okay, how can I help?
好吧 要我怎么帮忙
We need to find answers. You knew Metro Man best.
我们需要找到答案 你最了解都市侠
Did he have a hideout, a cave, a solitary fortress of some kind?
他有洞穴或私人要塞那样的藏身之处吗
Anything that would give us clues.
任何线索都行
Well, there is one place I know.
我知道一个地方
Roxanne: You gave him these powers, can't you just take them away?
你给了他超能力 难道就不能收回么
I can't, I lost my diffuser gun when I misplaced the invisible car.
不行 我忘记把隐形车停哪儿了 解构枪落在车里
The night you dumped me.
那个晚上 你甩了我
Alone.
让我独自一人
In the rain.
在雨中忧伤
-Did you ever look back? -NO!
- 你回过头吗 - 没
-Oh, my giant blue head. -I guess we're here.
- 疼 我的脑瓜 - 我们想我们到了
So, this is where he hid it.
这儿就是他的藏身之处
After all these years. My old shhool house.
过了这么多年啊 我的鞋校
You know, I think there's an apology in order, for the other night.
我觉得 我该为那天晚上的事情道歉
Okay that would be nice. But make it quick.
听起来不错 请长话短说
We have much more pressing matters to deal with.
还有很多事情要解决呢
Wow, can't believe he kept all this stuff.
哇 难以置信 这些东西他竟然全留着
Aww, I remember when he wore that.
我记得他穿那件披风
Can we try to stay focused here?
能专心点儿么
Yes of course, you're right, focused.
当然 你说的对 要专心点
HEY! Come over and look at this.
嘿 过来看
What is it? What did you find?
怎么了 发现啥了
Um.....look!
呃...看
This glass has ice cubes in it.
杯子里还有冰块
Yes, that's what happens when water gets cold.
对啊 水冷的时候就会结冰
No, what I'm saying is,
不对 我是想说
don't you think it's a little odd that the ice hasn't melted yet?
你不觉得没融化的冰块透着古怪吗
One of life's great mysteries.
人生之一大谜题啊
Hey.
嘿
AAAAAAAAH!
啊啊啊啊啊
TV News Anchor: We now have a confirmed report.
我们为您带来可靠报道
Tighten, first thought to be the City's new hero, has turned evil.
Tighten 我们曾以为的城市新英雄 现在已成为邪恶化身
The city has never seen this level of destruction.
这座城市从未遭受如此残忍的破坏
If only Metro Man were still alive.
如果都市侠还活着
-You're alive? -You're alive.
- 你还活着? - 你还活着
I'm alive.
我还活着
Roxanne: But..we..we saw your skeleton.
但我们...看到了你的骸骨...
-You were dead. -Are you a ghost?
- 你应该死了 - 你是鬼魂吗
There had better be, an amazing explanation for this.
你最好给个万分合理的解释
Speak, apparition.
说啊 幽灵先生
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
好吧 好吧
You both deserve the truth.
你们应该知道真相
It all started back at the observatory.
事情要从天文台说起
Roxanne was kidnapped, I was gonna stop you.
Roxanne被绑架了 我要去阻止你
My head wasn't in the game that day.
那天我脑抽了
We were kinda going through the motions. So...
我们的争斗就像走过场 所以...
Using my super speed.
我用了超速能力
I decided to go clear my head.
决定让头脑清醒一下
Then I realized we had done this same silly charade our entire lives.
随后我意识到 我们一直都在 重复而愚蠢的角色扮演
I tried to get my mind off how I was feeling.
我想要从这种思绪中摆脱出来
But I just felt stuck.
但就是钻了牛角尖
I began to realize, despite all my powers,
我意识到 虽然我有超能力
each and every citizen of Metro had something I didn't.
但所有市民都拥有一样我没有的东西
A choice.
选择
Ever since I can remember I've always had to be what the City wanted me to be.
自打我记事以来 我一直是这个城市的傀儡
But what about what I wanted to do?
但我的梦想怎么办呢
Then it suddenly hit me.
我茅塞顿开
I do have a choice.
我也有选择权
I can be whatever I want to be.
我想当什么就当什么
No one said this hero thing had to be a life time gig.
没人说过我必须做一辈子的英雄
You can't just quit either.
你也不能就这样抽身退出啊
That's when I got the brilliant idea...
所以我有了个绝妙的主意
...to fake my death.
假死
Copper drains my powers!
铜抑制了我的力量!
You're weakness is copper?
你的弱点是铜?
Once your death ray hit.
你的死亡射线从天而降
I never felt so alive.
我感到前所未有的自由
So I borrowed a prop from a nearby nursing school.
我从附近的护理学校里借来骷髅教具
Metro Man was finally dead.
都市侠终于死了
And Music Man was born.
音乐男就此诞生
Music man?
音乐男?
That way I can keep my logo.
那样我就不用改标志了
- WHAT? -'Cause of what?
- 神马? - 你神马意思?
Finally I'm free, to get in touch with my true power.
我终于自由了 还发现了我真正的力量
Weaving lyrical magic.
谱写音乐巨作
Check this out.
听听这个
- That's horrible. - Granted you have talent,
- 糟糕透顶 - 非常高兴您还有音乐才能
But there's a mad man out there destroying our...your city.
但现在外面有个疯子在破坏 我们的...你的城市
How could you do this?
你怎么能袖手旁观
The people of the city relied on you,
整座城市的人民都仰赖你
and you deserted them. You left us in the hands of, him!
但你抛弃了他们 让我们成为刀俎上的鱼肉...他的!
No offense.
无意冒犯
No, I'm with you.
不 我和你是一边的
Look, we need your help.
听着 我们需要你的帮助
I'm sorry, I really am.
我很抱歉 我真的是
Um, I'm, I'm done.
Um 我已经厌倦了
You know, little buddy. There's a Ying for every Yang.
知道吗 小家伙 有阴就有阳
Metro Man: If there's bad, good will rise up against it.
如果世间存有邪恶 正义必会声张
Metro Man: It's taken me a long time to find my calling.
我花了很久才找到自己
Now it's about time, you find yours.
现在是时候了 找到你自己
Roxanne: Hey, who needs him.
嘿 谁需要他
Roxanne: We can beat Tighten ourselves.
我们自己可以打败Tighten
I say we go back to the evil lair. Grab some ray guns,
我说我们回恶魔巢穴 拿上雷射抢
hold them sideways, and just go all gangsta on 'em.
呼朋唤友 武装起来
We can't
我们不行
So that's it? You're just giving up?
就这样? 你放弃了?
I'm the bad guy.
我是个坏人
I don't save the day. I don't fly off into the sunset,
我不会拯救城市 我不会迎着落日飞去
and I don't get the girl.
而且我得不到女孩的芳心
I'm going home.
我要回家了
TV reporter: Unless someone comes to our aid soon,
除非有人伸出援手
all may be lost.
一切将会毁灭
Thousands have already fled the city in a mass exodus.
数以千计的市民已经逃离了这座城市
Remaining citizens are warned, to stay indoors until further notice.
余下的被迫在家等候进一步的消息
Authorities have issued a warning, to stay out of the downtown area at all costs.
当局发出警告 不惜代价撤离市区
Hal!
Hal!
Let me guess, after seeing how awesome I am,
我猜猜 看到我有多牛逼之后
you've finally come to your senses.
你终于觉悟了
Well, I'm over you.
我对你已经没有兴趣了
I've come to stop you, Hal.
我是来阻止你 Hal
You? Oh, well. Okay, what are you going to do, report me to death?
你? 哦 好吧 你要怎么做 把我给我报死?
I was going to try reasoning with you.
我会试着劝阻你的
You and I, we worked together for a long time.
你和我 我们一起工作 很长时间了
I know you.
我了解你
You don't know me.
你不了解
You never took the time to know me.
你从不曾花时间来了解我
This is the first time we've hung out socially. And it's when I'm about to destroy the city.
这是我们第一次在工作之余见面 也是我快要毁灭这座城市的时候
I want to talk to the real Hal.
我想要和真正的Hal谈谈.
I want to talk to the guy who loved being a camera man, and eating dip,
我要的是那个喜爱自己的职业 也喜爱吃调味料的家伙
And being a nerd and being not as scary as the Tighten-Hal.
有些书呆子 却没有Tighten这么恐怖
To late!
太晚了!
Megamind.
超级大坏蛋
You and I have some unfinished business.
你和我还有帐要算
I'll be waiting at Metro Tower, oh, and just so you don't get cold feet.
我会等在都市塔 噢 可别临阵脱逃
Roxanne!
Roxanne!
Come on Roxi, call for your hero to come rescue you.
来啊 Roxi 呼唤你的英雄来救你啊
Megamind.
超级大坏蛋
I don't even know if you're listening, but if you are...
我甚至不知道你在不在听 如果你听到了...
You can't give up.
你不能放弃
The Megamind I knew would never have run from a fight.
我认识的超级大坏蛋决不会临阵退缩
Even when he knew he had absolutely no chance of winning.
即使他知道自己毫无胜算
It was your best quality.
这是你最可贵的品质
You need to be that guy, right now.
你必须站出来 就是现在
The city needs you.
这座城市需要你
I need you.
我需要你
Roxanne.
Roxanne
You have one hour. Don't...keep me waiting.
你有一个小时 别让我等太久哦
Warden, Warden!
典狱长 典狱长!
Listen to me, you have to let me go. Tighten has to be stopped.
听我说 你一定要放我走 得有人去阻止Tighten
Sorry Megamind, you still have 88 life sentences to go.
对不起 超级大坏蛋 你还有88个终身监禁
Plenty of time to reflect on what you've done.
时间足够你来反省自己的所作所为
If you want to hear me say it? I'll say it.
如果你想听我说?我会说的
Here it is. From the blackest part of my heart.
听好了 发自我内心最黑暗的地方
I....AM....Sorry!
对....不....起!
Not buying it.
我不吃这套
I don't blame you.
我不怪你
Megamind: I've terrorized the city countless times.
我危害城市数不清多少次了
Created a hero who's turned out to be a villain.
创造的英雄却变成了恶棍
I lied to Roxanne.
我骗了Roxanne
My best friend, Minion.
我最好的朋友 Minion
I treated like dirt.
我却当作垃圾
Please, don't make this city,
拜托 不要让这座城市
don't make Roxanne pay for my wrong doings.
不要让 Roxanne为我的恶行负责
Apology accepted.
我接受你的道歉
Uh, Minion. You fantastic fish, you.
Minion 你这条给力的小鱼
What are we waiting for?
我们还在等什么?
We'd better get going.
我们快走吧
You got me!
你骗到我了!
Good luck, fellows.
好运 伙计
Megamind: We're gonna die!
我们送死去了!
Minion: Wait, what?
等等 什么?
Hey, Metro losers.
嘿 废物们
This is Metro Tower.
这里是 都市塔
Tighten: They say it's suppose to be a symbol of our cities strength.
它被认为是我们城市实力的一个标志
But, for me, it's a reminder of the day this woman ferociously ripped out my heart.
但是 对我来说 却象征着 这个女人残忍的撕碎了我的心
And I hate reminders.
我恨哪
HAL!
HAL!
Please don't do this.
不要这样
I know there's still good in you, Hal.
我知道你是个好人 Hal
You're so naive, Roxie.
你太天真了 Roxie
You see the good in everybody, even when it's not there.
你看到了所有人的好 即使他们名不副实
You're living a fantasy.
你生活在幻想里
There is no Easter bunny.
没有复活节兔子
There is no tooth fairy.
没有牙仙
And there is no Queen of England.
也没有英格兰女王
This is the real world. And you need to wake up.
这是现实世界 你快觉醒吧
You dare challenge Megamind?
你胆敢挑战 超级大坏蛋?
This town isn't big enough for two super villains.
一山容不得二虎
Oh, you're a villain all right.
哦 你确实是个恶棍
Just not a super one.
但不是最牛逼的那个
Yeah, what's the difference?
啊 有什么区别?
PRESENTATION!
演出开始!
I knew you'd come back.
我知道你会回来
Well, that makes one of us.
是你一厢情愿
-What's the plan? -Well, mostly involves, not dying.
- 有什么计划? - 主要是 保命要紧
I, like that plan.
我 喜欢
I can't control it.
我失去控制了
No!
不!
Well, that was easy.
呵 轻而易举
Looks like there's only one loose end now.
看来还剩一个
Please, let's have a little respect for public transportation.
拜托 还是对公共交通工具尊重点
You came back.
你回来了
You were right, Roxanne.
你说得对 Roxanne
I never should have left.
我从不该离开
Whoa, I...I thought you were dead.
哇 我 我以为你死了
My death was, greatly exaggerated.
我的死 说得太夸张了
So, you're the punk I've heard about.
那么 你就是那个我听到的小流氓
Ah!
噢!
I'm sorry, I did the best I could.
对不起 我尽力了
I'm so proud of you.
我为你骄傲
Minion?
Minion?
Surprise! Heh, heh, heh.
惊喜! 呵呵呵
He's the real hero.
他才是真英雄
Megamind.
超级大坏蛋
Going somewhere?
要去哪里?
Besides jail.
监狱吗
No, not in the face man, please.
不 不要打脸
If you know what's good for you, Tighten.
如果你明白什么是对的 Tighten
You'll stay out of Montrosity.
离开大都费
-You got it! -For good.
- 知道了 - 很好
Pretty sneaky, sis.
太狡猾了 兄弟
But there is only one person I know who calls this town, Montrosity.
我知道只有一个人会说大都费
Ooops.
啊呀
You!
你!
Bet you think it's really funny, huh?
你觉得很好玩吗 嗯?
Let's all laugh at the really cool guy, huh.
我们来看看谁才是可笑的
You're not going to be laughing for long.
你不会得意太久的
The invisible car. Hey, remember that night that I dumped you?
隐形车 嘿 记得那个我甩你的晚上吗?
You are bringing this up now?
现在提这个干吗?
I did look back.
我当时回头了
You did?
你回头了?
YOU DID!
你回头了!
Yes, and you should look back, right now.
对 你也应该回过头 马上
Oh, I get it.
Oh 我懂了
This is the last time you'll make a fool out of me.
这是你最后一次耍我了
I made you a hero.
我把你变成英雄
You did the fool thing, all by yourself.
是你自己搞砸了一切
You're so pathetic.
你太可悲了
No matter what side you're on.
不管你站哪一边
You're always the looser.
你总是那个失败者
There's a benefit to loosing.
有得就有失
You get to learn from your mistakes.
你要为你的错误付出代价
What?
什么?
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
哦  你是在跟我开玩笑吧!
Minion, if I live, I will kill you.
Minion 如果我还活着 一定要杀了你
Enjoy your flight.
好好享受吧
AAAAAAAAH!
啊 !
Megamind.
超级大坏蛋
Megamind Narrates: So, this is how it ends.
嗯 到此为止了
Normally I'd chalk this up to my last glorious failure.
通常 我都会更新在我的辉煌败绩中
But not today!
但不是今天!
What can I say?
我能说什么呢?
Old habits die hard.
狗改不了吃屎
Say bye, bye Roxie.
说再见吧 Roxie
Ollo.
内好
Thing about bad guys, they always LOOSE!
关于坏蛋 他们永远赢不了!
We did it, you won.
我们成功了 你赢了
Well, I finally had a reason to win.
最终 我找到了获胜的理由
You.
是你
MINION!
MINION!
Can't see it's cold and... warm, and dark and light.
没有冷和...热 光明与黑暗
It's me, Minion.
是我 Minion
I'm right here.
我在这儿
We've had a lot of adventures together.
我们一起经历多少风雨
You and I.
你和我
We have, Minion.
是的 Minion
I mean...
我说...
most of them ended in horrible failure, but,
大多数以惨败告终 但
We won today. Didn't we, sir?
今天我们赢了 是吗 主人?
Yes Minion, we did it.
对 Minion 我们赢了
Thanks to you.
谢谢你
Code-We're the good guys now.
我们是好人了
Code-I guess we are.
我想是的
Oh, oh. I'm going...I think this...
哦 我要去 我想...
This is it, I  mean I'm going far awa...
是了 我快要去了...
Oh, what a drama queen.
哎哟 真爱演啊
You know, I'm feeling much better now.
我现在感觉好多了
I guess I just needed a swim
我想我只是需要游下泳
-He had you, didn't he. -Whew!
- 他吓到你了 对吗 - 哇哦 !
Classic, Minion. Don't give them the face.
漂亮 Minion 别管他们
Megamind: There he is with that little face. Look at that face.
看他那小脸蛋儿
We did it!
我们赢了!我们赢了!
-Fist pump! -You did it!
- 给力! - 你赢了!
We won, we won, we won.
我们赢啦
What! Get back you savages!
什么 走开点 野蛮人!
Sorry, sorry. He's just not used to positive feedback.
抱歉抱歉 他还没习惯正面的回应
Funny, I guess destiny is not the path given to us.
真有趣 我想命运不是为我们铺好的路
But the path we choose for ourselves.
而是我们自己选择的路
All right, put your hands in the air.
好的 举起你们的双手
Now hand over your wallets.
现在交出你们钱包
I'm just kidding.
我只是开玩笑
Just kidding.
玩笑而已
I have to admit.
不得不承认
Being good, has its perks.
好人 还是有好报的
You know, you look pretty good in white.
看 你穿白色很不错哦
Megamind, if you please.
超级大坏蛋 请你
Uh, hey, my kid can't see.
嘿 我孩子看不到了
Sorry my friend.
对不起 朋友
Way to go, little buddy. I knew you had it in you.
真行啊 小家伙 我知道你可以的
Mayor: Ladies and gentlemen... MEGAMIND!
女士们先生们...超级大坏蛋!
Defender of Metro City.
大都市的守护者
You know, I like the sound of that.
知道吗 我喜欢这称呼
Hit it!
上音乐
I'm bad, I'm bad, that's right
我很坏 我很坏 就是这样